救命
Help!
Help me!
我的干呕症状消失了  我也该离开了
Dry heaves are gone, so am I.
我去跟医生核实一下
I'll check with the doctor.
大可不必了
No, no, no, no.
我是自愿进来的  跟我确认就够了
I'm here voluntarily, just got to check with me.
抱歉  诺兰医生特别嘱咐过
I'm sorry. Dr. Nolan left specific instructions.
她没生病  只是恐惧  所以让她说
She's not sick. She's scared. So tell her to tell
原来还是个是黑人总管
And he's black.
那我以为你会对奴隶事件更敏感一点
I thought you'd be a little more sensitive on the slavery issue.
你们不能留我
Can't keep me.
豪斯医生  你看起来好多了
Dr. House, you look a lot better.
我的确是好多了
I am a lot better
不需要止痛药了  幻觉消失
No painkillers, no Hallucinations.
腿还是痛  但并无大碍
Leg hurts, but it's manageable.
你很出色
Great job.
我会想你的
Gonna miss you.
而且希望能尽快开始想你
Want to start missing you as soon as possible.
从法律上讲  你随时可以离开
Well, legally, you're free to go whenever you want.
不过我建议你留下来
But I suggest you stay.
我会好好考虑的
I'll take it under advisement.
如果你认为你产生幻觉是由
If you thought the hallucinations
维科丁引起的
Were from your vicodin problem,
你为什么不去戒毒中心呢
Why didn't you just check yourself into a rehab facility?
我那时候被误导以为自己可能疯了
I was deluded into thinking I might be crazy.
你已经滥用维科丁这么多年
But you had been abusing vicodin for years.
从未出现过幻觉  失眠
Never had delusions, never had trouble sleeping
除了有自恋和反动倾向之外
Never had any problems.
从未出现过任何问题
Other than narcissism and antisocial behavior,
直到你的两名手下死去
Until two colleagues died.
令尊过世
Your father died.
你的病根远比维科丁深
Your issues run deeper than vicodin.
这些话才不能让我重新振作  对吧
Well, that's not gonna cheer me up, is it?
你需要转到我们的长期住院区
You need to be transferred to our long-term ward,
开始用药物和谈心疗法
Started on medication, talk therapy
我知道了
Yeah, I get it.
只是我还有一个心病未了
Uh, just one thing I'm getting hung up on.
那就是我能来去自如
I can leave whenever I want.
先解决这个问题怎么样呢
How about I start with that?
你不能回去行医
You can't go back to practicing medicine.
我不想行医
I don't want to practice medicine.
我决定要做宇航员
I've decided I want to be an astronaut.
如果你想拿国家宇航员执照的话
Well, if you want your state astronaut's license,
就需要我的推荐信
You're gonna need my recommendation.
这是流行的新式疗法吗
Is that a popular, new treatment
敲诈吗
Blackmail?
你要好起来
You need to get better.
欢迎来到六号病房
Welcome to Ward Six.
老实说要我来这干嘛
So brass tacks what do I have to do
要呆在这里多久呢
And how long do I have to be here?
这取决于你  疗程很简单
Depends on you. Process Is pretty basic.
如果你配合治疗  按时吃药
If you follow the schedule, agree to take meds
参与集体和个体治疗
Participate in group and individual therapy,
-我们能为目标奋斗  -我定了一个目标
- We can work on goals. - I set a goal.
很不错  是什么目标呢
Excellent. What is it?
我的目标就是让你的老板
My goal is to get your boss
写那封我想要他写的推荐信
To write the letter that I want him to write.
来谈谈我们的疗程
Now let's talk process.
我能挤出灿烂笑容  也能对人友善
I can smile through gritted teeth and play nice,
但这么做我会冒着大开杀戒的风险
But there are serious risks of violence involved in that choice,
所以我选择大闹天宫
So I'm going with turning this ward upside down,
让你和你老板的工作和生活都苦不堪言
Making you and your boss' job and life so unmanageable
让他逼不得已给出一纸承诺来摆脱我
That he'll write whatever he has to write to get rid of me.
他的东西都准备好了
He's all set.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不要保镖  滚开
Yo, I don't need an escort. Get off me.
你是谁
Who are you?
你相信这些家伙吗
You believe these guys?
逼我上躁狂抑郁症的课程
Lecturing me on manic depression,
好像我自己不能书一样
Like I couldn't write a book or two.
我停止服药药  因为我想停止服药
I stop taking my meds, because I want to stop taking my meds,
因为我根本没病
Because nothing is wrong with me.
没理由把我拽回这里
No reason to keep dragging me back here.
如果开始吃药  一切都会放缓
When I'm on them, everything slows down.
那才是问题所在
That's when the problem is.
很高兴见到你
Hey, nice to see you.
我上个室友不能忍受我
My roommate last time couldn't stand me.
真的吗
Relly
我是胡安·阿瓦  胡瓦是我的艺名
I'm Juan Alvarez. J.A.'s my stage name.
不过这里的人都叫我阿瓦
But Alvie's what everybody around here calls me,
就像伍迪·艾伦在"安妮·霍尔"演的角色
Like the Woody Allen character in, uh, Annie Hall,
不过是波多黎各版本  也没那么神经质
But the Puerto Rican version and not as neurotic.
该怎么称呼你呢
So what do I call you?
你这次才真的在等我回答
You're actually waiting for an answer this time.
你可以叫我豪斯
You can call me House.
等等我
Hey, wait up.
我在这里跟每个人都熟透了
I've already got the whole place wired
所以能带你熟悉一下
So I'll give you the rundown.
大家好
Yo, everybody!
这是我的新室友  豪斯
This Is my new roommate, House, y'all.
你要知道的就是
Main thing you got to know
这有电话吗
Is this the line?
加比  认识下我的新室友  豪斯
Hey, Gabby, meet my new roommate, House.
你也可以叫他"西斯"
You can call him "Heezy"
绝不可以
No, you can't.
别紧张  她不会叫的
Don't worry. She won't call you anything.
她已经有大概十年没开口说话了
She hasn't talked in, like, ten years or something.
你能跟我走走真好
Good you came here.
你得熟悉地形
You need to know the lay of the land.
我要换房间
I need to request a new room.
你太有意思了
Ha ha. You're funny.
这里是你拿药的地方
You're also gonna come here to get your meds.
我不用吃药
I'm not on any meds.
你也不用吗  恭喜啊
You either? Good for you.
说我脑子转太快
Tell me my mind works too fast.
干嘛不说博尔特跑太快
Probably tell Usain Bolt he runs too fast.
有人在吗
Excuse me.
我知道你们故意不理我  但是我的冰箱空了
I know you're busy ignoring me, but my minibar is empty.
你觉得博尔特可以跳远吗
You think Bolt could do the long jump?
那项运动需要向前发展
That sport needs to evolve.
同样的世界纪录已经保持了二十年
Had the same world record for, like, 20 years.
我觉得如果一个人头朝前冲
I think if one guy launched himself headfirst
刚好在他落地之前
And right before he hits the ground
去做一个前翻
Does a front flip instead,
能轻易多跳出三米
Get three extra feet out of that, easy.
你去创那个记录吧
Go be that man.
我的头
Aah! My head!
我的头好痛
My head! oh!
我们不会给你长安静的[精神病药物]
You're not getting any Haldol.
不好意思
Sorry.
他是哈尔  他的真名是康纳
That's Hal. His real name is Connor,
我们叫他哈尔  是因为他
But we call him Hal, because he
行了  我知道了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I got it.
我们不能弹那个
We can't play that.
他们锁起来了
They keep it locked up.
我希望能给我们弹  可是
I wish we could, but at the same time,
你可以想象弹琴时会多么烦人
You can imagine how annoying that could be.
疯人会一直弹一直弹
Crazy people playing on it all the time
我们将永无宁日
We'd never get any peace.
跟我来  我介绍你给大家认识
Come on, I want to introduce you to everybody.
你觉得他是认真的吗
Do you think he's serious?
他是位医生
He's a doctor.
他明知自己轻举妄动只会增强我们的诊断
He knows that acting out will only reinforce our diagnosis.
要么会管用
Or it'll work.
你真的认为我们要担心的是这件事吗
You actually think this is something we should be concerned about?
你应该担心的是能威胁他人的病人
A patient makes a threat, you should always be concerned.
我们的家族里又添两名新成员
There are two new additions to our ward.
大家都认识  阿瓦
You all know Alvie.
谢谢  感谢大家  请别鼓掌
Thank you, thank you. Hold your applause.
很高兴重回梅菲尔德
It's great to be back here in Mayfield,
不仅是为了食物
Not just for the food,
也不仅是为了美女
Not just for the ladies
也许就是为了美女才回来的
Well, okay, maybe just for the ladies.
也请欢迎格雷戈
And you should also welcome Greg to the floor.
名字记不住就算了  我们只是萍水相逢
Don't worry about the name. I'm just passing through.
不想让哪位伤心落泪
Don't want to break any hearts.
我们现在能出去吗
Can we go outside now?
现在还不行  杰
Not now, Jay.
他患有幽闭恐惧症  对吧
So he's Claustrophobic, right?
你有幽闭恐惧症吗
You're Claustrophobic?
能给我笔把这些东西记下来吗
Can I get a pen to write this stuff down?
你去哪里
Where are you going?
他要去哪
Where's he going?
没事的
It's okay.
妄想症  确诊
Paranoid, check.
比斯利医生...
Dr. Beasley...
我在食物方面有些问题
I am having an issue with the food.
是什么问题呢
What's the problem?
我已经吃得越来越少
I swear I'm eating less and less,
我却还是越长越胖
And I just keep getting bigger and bigger.
谁有蜡笔吗
A crayon? Anybody?
我们下次再谈
We'll talk about it another time.
我知道大家昨天都参加了艺术疗法
I understand you all had art therapy yesterday.
也许我们可以把新的作品挂在墙上
Maybe we can hang some of the new pieces on the wall.
你割过腕  是么
Cut your wrists, huh?
格雷戈  有些话题
Greg, there are certain topics
不好意思
Oh, I'm sorry.
这里有自杀禁令吗
Is suicide taboo?
糟了  要是我第一天就坏了规矩
Gosh, if I've broken a rule on my first day,
那我就死了算了
I will kill myself.
集会结束
Group's over.
真是时光飞逝啊
That flew by.
你要知道你可不是这里
You realize you're not the first
第一位不合作的患者
Uncooperative patient on this floor.
-真的吗  他们有俱乐部吗  -有啊
- Really? Is there a club? - Yes.
跟我到会所去吧
Come with me to the Clubhouse.
你才来没多久啊
That didn't take long?
我太优秀了
I'm that good.
加油  阿瓦
Come on, Alvie!
动起来啊
Let's see some action!
你抢不到的
You got nothing!
传  传  快传  好
Pass, pass, pass! Good.
加油  伙计们
Come on, guys!
准备好待人友善了吗
Ready to play nice?
如果我说"准备好了"  你会信吗
Would you believe me if I said yes?
不会
No.
那么  我准备好了
Then, yes.
你知道我在努力帮你
You do know I'm trying to help you.
我也知道你是故作温柔体贴  工作有效率
I also know you're trying to be sweet, caring, and effective.
只是你不是这样的人
You're just not.
你想离开
You want out.
那就聊一聊吧  拿出真诚
Just talk. Be honest.
试着与人共事
Try to work with people.
试着与人交往
Try to deal with people.
好
Okay.
豪斯  豪斯  他归我这队
House, House! He's on my team!
闭嘴  没人喜欢你
Shut up. Nobody likes you.
-我挡着你了吗  -什么
- Am I crowding you? - What?
不见天日了  对吧
Can't see the sun? Huh?
别啊  一切都在逼近
Oh, no, everything is closing in.
够了  给你
Okay, okay.
够了
Okay.
他是有幽闭恐惧症的那位  对吧
He's the claustrophobic one, right?
我是单凭记忆而已
Cause I'm doing it from memory.
你得运球才行
You have to dribble.
为什么
Why?
中情局的卫星又没在监视我
The CIA satellites aren't watching me.
他们监视的是你
They're watching you,
因为你穿着大绿色衣服
Cause you're wearing green.
动个指头就搞定这个了
That one was just too easy.
真的吗  厌食症吗
Seriously, anorexia?
你想别人把你当作娘娘腔吗
What, are you supposed to be a girl?
还有  关于你那个隐晦问题的答案
And in answer to your implicit question,
是的  你的裤子让你看起来很胖
Yes, those pants do make you look fat.
你在急诊室里醒来时有多沮丧
How upset were you when you woke up in the E.R.
发现自己苟延残喘  仍是个窝囊废
And you were still alive and a failure?
酷啊  二比零  漂亮
Whoo-hoo! 2-0, good guys!
你说得对  伸出援手的确让人受益匪浅
You're right. It is rewarding when you reach out.
你不能上楼  现在是场地活动时间
You can't go up there. It's yard time right now.
那就写小报告吧
Put it on my tab.
"童年情景"  舒曼
"Kinderszenen opus 15" -- Schumann
音乐疗法应该是
I think you'll find music therapy's
对着病人弹才更有效
More effective if the patients are inside to hear it.
你从哪儿弄到钥匙的呢
Where'd you get the key?
他们给我的
They gave it to me.
要是她开尊口的话
So if she ever talks,
会是德国口音吗
Are we gonna get a German accent?
才不是
No.
她是我小姑子
She's, um, my husband's sister.
那就让他来弹琴
So let him come play the piano.
他不会弹琴
He doesn't know how to play.
弹得不错
Nice.
不过右脚力道过重
You're a little heavy on the right foot, though.
看到她的头了吗
See her head?
随着音乐轻轻点着
It bobs to the music.
这是她给我的唯一的回应
It's the only real reaction I'm getting from her.
就像我们在聊天
It feels like we're talking.
你没在聊天
You're not talking.
她的头是随着脉搏点动
Her head is bobbing to her pulse.
你是新来的医生吗
Are you a new doctor on the ward?
技术上来书  是
Technically, yes.
这次能让我带路么
Can I lead this time?
你弹完了之后别锁盖子
Leave the lid unlocked when you're done.
你能随手关门吗
Can you close the door?
冷气都给你放走了
You're letting all the cool air out.
如果你继续负隅顽抗的话
If you keep up this scorched-earth policy,
你的就要永远被关在这里
You're gonna end up living in this room.
准备采用新战略了吗
Are you ready to try another strategy,
还是想我把你丢在这里
Or do you want me to leave you in here?
二比一  我赢了  看  豪斯回来了
2-1, that's game. Hey, House is back.
我来捡球
I'll get the ball.
来吧  我要来点猛的
Come on, I need some meat.
没人敢跟我玩了
I got no one left to play.
我来和你玩
I'll play you.
妞儿  来吧  豪斯
Girl. Come on, House.
你来计分
You can serve.
对于我之前的所作所为我一直很愧疚
I've had some time to think about the approach I've been taking.
我在这里闷闷不乐
I knew I'm unhappy here,
而且我把怨气都撒在你们身上
And I，I've been taking it out on you guys...
这对你们不公平
Unfairly.
我那是...
It was...
迁怒于你们
Misdirected anger.
可仔细想想  这里真正的混蛋
Cause when you think about it, the real jerks here...
-应该是那些医生  -豪斯
- Are the doctors. - House!
他们给你们乒乓球桌
See how they give you a ping-pong table,
却没不给你们拍子和网
But no paddles, no net?
把你们当傻子耍
It's like they're mocking you.
赞同
Preach!
这是桌上网球  而非桌上排球
The game is called table tennis, not table volleyball.
格雷戈  你明知会有结束的
Greg, you know where this is gonna end.
有人见过没有网的网球场吗
Who ever saw a tennis court without a net?
我家对面的街头公园有三个网球场
Little run-down park across from my apartment growing up
没有网  从来就没人用
Three courts, no nets. No one ever used it.
我们才不会那球网上吊呢
No one's gonna try to hang themselves with a ping-pong net
-当然不会  -荒唐至极
- Of course not. - Yeah, that's ridiculous.
医生你们有错  你们把我们当屁孩使唤
It ain't right, doc. You treat us like little kids.
不对  屁孩都可以玩乒乓球
No, little kids are allowed to play ping-pong,
他们还能弹钢琴呢
And they can play the piano.
是啊  还比不上小屁孩呢
Yeah, worse than little kids.
很好  我们不如先离开这里  坐下来
All right, why don't we just go and sit down
-慢慢商量  -不  不
- And discuss it? - No, no, no.
我现在就要在这里商量
No, I want to discuss it right here.
伙计们
Guys.
Guys
伙计们
Guys!
豪斯说得对
House is right.
我觉得大家都能应付这个
I think everyone here can handle these.
开什么玩笑
Seriously?
那就是你的策略
Is that your strategy
除了我  让每个人都如愿以偿吗
Give everybody what they want except me?
你是天生的领导
You're a natural leader.
你在这能有大作为
You could do something useful down here,
为了他们  也为了你自己
For them, definitely for you.
要么我们可以一直抗战下去
Or we could keep fighting...
要是你以为你能摧毁我
If you think you can break me,
要是你以为我没有你那么顽固
If you think I'm not every bit as stubborn as you.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你会继续让他们痛苦吗
So you gonna keep trying to make them miserable?
不了
No.
新计划吗
New plan?
是的
Yep.
是什么
What Is it?
还不知道
I don't know yet.
在安静的环境下更容易想出新计划
You know, it's easier to come up with a new plan in silence.
对  酷
Right. Cool.
我能哼歌吗
Can I hum?
[梅菲尔德精神病院]
Mayfield Psychiatric Hospital
大家请热烈欢迎
I'd like you all to welcome
我们家族的新成员
Another new addition to our wardsteve.
请叫我自由战士
Uh, Freedom Master.
史蒂夫·埃尔克
Steve Elkerton
只是伪装
Is just a cover.
就像克拉克·肯特[超人]或
It's like Clark Kent or
布鲁斯·韦恩[蝙蝠侠]或彼得·帕克[蜘蛛侠]
Bruce Wayne or Peter Parker.
真酷
Cool.
我们这里的耶稣比超人多
We got more Jesuses than superheroes.
我努力融入外面的世界
Well, I try to blend in the outside world,
但我发现只有在这里  大家才能理解
But I figure in here, everybody gets it.
我们住在正义病房里
We're living in the ward of justice.
阿瓦
Alvie
你可以再解释一下你觉得
Can you explain a little more
每个人都理解什么吗
About what you think everybody gets?
世界上总是有正义与邪恶
There's good and evil in the world.
有些人是  是特别的
And some people are...are special,
他们被选中去驱逐世间邪恶
And they're chosen to help keep evil forces at bay.
你以为自己能把子弹停下来  对吧
You don't think you can stop bullets, do you?
我躲开它们
I move out of their way.
你能读心吗
Can you read minds?
不行
No.
这是团体讨论时间  格雷戈
It's group time, Greg.
她为什么不说话呢
Why isn't she talking?
她需要帮助
She needs help.
她需要有人拯救她
She needs somebody to save her.
这就是我们努力去做的
That's what we're all trying to do.
休息五分钟
Let's take five minutes.
大家都跟史蒂夫聊聊
Everybody get to know Steve.
我能飞
I can fly.
我知道你在密谋着
I know you are scheming
离开这里的完美计划
Working on your next elaborate plan to get out of here.
为什么不先等几天
Why don't you put the plan on hold for a few days?
看会有什么结果呢
See what happens.
让我好好工作
Just let me do my job.
如果你喜欢个人活动而不是团体活动
If you prefer private to group, we can do that.
也行  或许可以吃些抗抑郁药
Maybe try some SSRIs.
如果觉得不见成效
If you think nothing's working,
你再施行你的惊天大计也不迟
You can always go back to your schemes.
你两分钟之前跟我说这些就好了
God. If only you'd said that two minutes ago,
刚好赶在我的新计划诞生之前
Before I came up with my new scheme.
现在我要采取行动了
Now I'm committed.
懂吗
Get it?
你有三楼特权吗
Do you have third-floor privileges?
从我分享我叔叔怎样宠之后就有了
Ever since I shared in group about my uncle fondling me.
是真的吗
Is that true?
是的  我能用三楼的自动售卖机
Yeah. And now I can use the third-floor vending machines.
你吃酸奶雪糕和洋葱片吗
You eat sour cream and onion chips?
酱料才是关键
I mean, the whole point is the dipping.
以前我们为图方便没有将酸奶雪糕混进去
Sure, we save time by not adding the mix and sour cream,
那样你就错过了美味
But you're missing out on the...
我要你去诺兰的办公室
I need you to break into Nolan's office.
突击队行动
Commando style.
给我听清楚咯
I want you to focus.
你要我给他捣乱吗
You want me to mess him up?
潜进诺兰的办公室
Go into Nolan's office.
看他的日程
Look at his calendar.
找到他在今天十一点见的那个女人名字
I need the name of the woman he met with at 11:00 today.
没问题  我还可以给你买老式薯条
No problem. And I'll get you some old-school chips.
如果有  我还能拿些酱
If they have them, I'll get you some dip,
但我从来没见过自动贩卖机里有酱
But I've never seen dip in the vending machine.
够了  给我买薯条和酱
Yes, get me chips and dip.
还有不明白的吗
What else?
我懂了  我懂了  B计划
I get it, I get it. Plan "B."
B计划是勒索  我掩护你
"B" is for blackmail. I got you covered.
突击队行动
Commando style.
放开我
Let me go!
我就想买点零食
I just wanted a little snack.
你们不能这么对我
That ain't right!
我不知道机器被搬走了
I didn't know the machine was moved!
我想吃乐之饼干
I want some Ritz Bits!
我好像怀孕了  我饿啊
I might be pregnant! I get these cravings!
找到名字没
You get the name?
诺兰在日程本正中间
Nolan's schedule book just has a big "X"
画了一个大写的X
Marking out the whole middle of the day.
可能和他在一起的女孩叫艳遇
Well, then we can assume the girl he's with is called "Nooner."
他想要"叉"她
He's gonna "fork" her.
他想要"切"她
He's gonna "kinfe" her.
我来不及检查电话
I didn't get a chance to check the phone
-和其他的东西  -没关系
- Or anything else. - That's okay.
我看到了她的车牌号
I got her license plate.
我打电话给我的朋友  他拿到名字
I call my friend. He gets the name.
我就可以拿到我要的信了
I get the letter that gets me out of here.
你可以用电话吗
You got phone privileges?
我的权限还是负4级  只能玩蜡笔
I'm on level minus four. I'm still writing with a crayon.
-你呢  -你至少要有5级权限
- You? - You got to be at level five.
像太空塔的顶端
That's like the top of the space needle.
哈尔是唯一有这高权限的
Hal's the only one that's up that high.
哈尔是五级
Hal's at level five?
他每洗一次盘子就得一分
They give him a point every time he clears his plate.
我一直帮他吃土豆
I've been eating his potatoes.
他会卖给你几分钟吗
Will he sell you some minutes?
才不会  我花了两根烟买他的土豆
No. I pay two cigarettes for the potatoes.
打电话要贵得多
Phone's worth a lot more.
你可以含着药不咽吗
Can you cheek a pill?
不能
No.
那就太可惜了
That's too bad for you.
你扛得住吗
You sure you're good with this?
行  没问题
Yeah, yeah.
尽管来
Got to be done.
要怎么开始
So how do we start?
直接开始就行
I think we just start.
干得漂亮些  逼真些
Make it good. Make it real.
动手吧
Just do it already.
格雷戈出事了
Code Gray!
给我5毫克长安静
Give me five milligrams of Haldol!
救命  把他拉开
Help! Get him off me!
喂他吃
Give it to him!
兄弟  刚才太棒了
Dude, that was awesome.
哈尔不会介意它们湿了吧
Think Hal will mind if they're wet?
豪斯
House?
不是  是你在收容所里的别的朋友
No, it's your other friend at the asylum.
怎么样了
How's it going?
幻觉消失了  所以是维柯丁
Hallucinations are gone, so is the vicodin.
腿怎么样了  还疼吗
How's the leg? How's the pain?
他们给我用了非麻醉制剂
They got me on some nonnarcotic.
我能忍住
I'm dealing.
我想让你查一个车牌
I need you to run a license plate.
你那里有肇事逃逸车主吗
Was there a hit-and-run on your floor?
豪斯  做你该做的事
House, just do what you're supposed to do.
听医生的话
Listen to the doctors,
我很快就可以去探访你了
And I'll be able to visit soon.
查到这辆车的车主
Track down the owner of this car,
我明天就可以
And I'll be able to visit you
去你办公室探访你了
In your office tomorrow.
我那医生老奸巨滑
My doctor is too smart,
老态龙钟  衣冠禽兽
Too old, and too well-dressed
才不会专心管理他的病房
To only be running one ward.
他的生活有过不轨
He screwed up something in his life,
我想他又重蹈覆辙了
And I think he's doing it again.
知道她的名字就可以反敲诈这个敲诈者了
I need her name so I can blackmail the blackmailer.
豪斯  豪斯
House，House.
他找过我了
He called me.
他想知道什么
What did he want to know?
他想了解你
He wanted to know about you.
他告诉我你会打电话求我
He wanted to warn me that you'd be calling for something.
还告诉我如果我想让你好起来
And he told me if I wanted to help you get better,
就不能插手他的工作
I had to let him do his job.
现在我打给你  是告诉你如果他找你
Well, now I'm calling you to tell you that if he calls you...
豪斯  对不起  我很想帮你
House, I'm so sorry. I wish I could help you.
你就能帮
You can.
猜怎么着
It turns out...
你是我唯一的朋友
You're my only friend.
豪斯说艳遇小姐就在楼下
House said the Nooner now living on the floor
还有我讨厌你
And I hate you.
我决定合作
I'm gonna cooperate.
这才不是你的计划  这是他们的计划
That's not much of a plan. That's actually their plan.
是的  他们的计划就是
No, I'm pretty sure their plan Is for me
让我把药真正咽下去
To actually swallow the pills,
让我真正合作
To actually cooperate.
我为我的小室友骄傲
I'm so proud of my little roomie.
我只是教了些他都知道的东西
I only taught him everything he knows.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
好了  跺脚狂人  从你开始下注
Okay, Stomp, you start the betting.
牌面最大的赢
Highest card wins.
他不跟了
That's probably a fold.
里克特
Richter.
两支烟
Two cigarettes.
他都焉了  阿瓦
He's not confident, Alvie.
用你的押韵句子盖过他
Crush him, in the form of a rhyme if you want.
送烟舞会矣
No regrets return cigarette
有只小二还下这么大注
Whoa, that's a lot of nerve
真是胆大包天啊
For someone with a two on their head.
你休想蒙我
You're messing with me.
你不能超过十  我只有五支烟
You can't raise ten. I only have five.
出你的电话卡
Throw in your phone card.
我才不会出我的电话卡
I'm not gonna throw in my phone card.
我可以玩吗
Can I play?
-过来  -干嘛
- Come here. - Why?
我看你够不够格
I want to see if you've got what it takes.
来张最凶的扑克脸
Give me your best poker face.
我挺不住了
Too rich for my blood.
你来替我吧
You can take my seat.
吃药时间到
Med time!
今天觉得怎么样
How are you feeling today?
比昨天好些  没有明天好
Better than yesterday, not as good as tomorrow.
我给她哼过歌
I've been humming to her.
她随节奏摆动
She sways.
音乐可能真的有用
It might be significant.
你在装作无视我
Are you ignoring me,
还是已经被我迷得神魂颠倒了呢
Or are you just letting my charm wash over you?
我不能边弹琴边聊天
Kind of tough to play and chat.
几星期前你跟我说
A couple of weeks ago, you told me
对她弹琴简直是浪费时间
Playing to her was a complete waste of time.
你说的没错
You're right.
你真的不能边聊天边弹琴
Your playing does get worse when you talk.
我想她很喜欢音乐
I assume she loved music.
她以前在费城交响乐团
She played for the Philadelphia Philharmonic...
弹奏大提琴
Cello.
如果她对钢琴有反应
Well, if she responded to the piano,
大提琴效果应该更好
She might respond even better to the cello.
我会拉一点点
I play a little.
或许星期二可以带过来
Maybe I'll bring one in Tuesday.
谢谢
Thank you.
桌子变了  医生也变了
Different desk, different doctor.
你已经用药一段时间了
You've been on meds for a while now.
我要定期检查
I'll be checking in with you periodically
看是否需要调整剂量
To see if we need to adjust your dose.
有没有感觉口干或失眠
Any dry mouth, trouble sleeping?
没有
Nope.
我可以走了吗
Can I go now?
有个躁狂病人拿着一盒烟在等我
There's a manic out there with a fresh carton of cigarettes,
还是个典型的吹牛大王
And he's a terrible bluffer.
很高兴看到你和阿瓦重归于好
It's nice to see that you and Alvie are friends again.
说说你们上次打的那一架
Tell me about your fight.
他打我  我揍回去
He hit me. I hit him back.
直到咱俩都筋疲力尽
Repeat until pulpy.
阿瓦说是你挑起来的
Alvie told me you instigated the thing.
大家不都是这样吗
Well, that tends to be the way fights work
公说公有理  婆说婆有理
Different interpretations of the same circumstances.
很通情达理啊
Very understanding attitude.
有来怪腔怪调了
There's that tone again.
你很聪明
You're smart.
为什么你每次在恭维我
How come every time you compliment me,
听上去都像是在指责我
It sounds like an accusation?
你吃了那么多药物却无副作用  这不正常
You're not having any side effects from your meds, which Is unusual.
哪有什么不正常
It's not that unusual.
你关于打架的说辞合情合理
The story about the fight isn't adding up.
别再假装好像
Why don't you stop pretending
你心中没有定论一样可以吗
That you haven't reached a conclusion?
你不信任我
You don't trust me.
事实上  你打心眼里讨厌我
Actually, it's more fundamental than that. You don't like me.
我可没说过
I didn't say that.
你认为我没吃药
You think I'm not taking my meds.
你吃了吗
Are you?
当然
Yes.
你到底想让我干什么
So what do you want me to do?
做个尿检吗
Want me to take a urine test?
这样能赢取你的信任吗
Will that earn your trust?
的确如此
Actually, yeah.
尿在里面
Have at it.
请给我留点尊严
A little dignity, please.
你知道规定  我必须监视
You know the rules. I have to watch.
可你大可不必抢占场边座位
Yeah, but you don't have to have courtside seats.
让我在隔间解决行吗
Can I at least use a stall?
趁热抓住了
Get it while it's hot.
我抱歉刚才怀疑你
I'm sorry I doubted you.
自由战士
Freedom Master,
能帮我个忙吗
Think you could help me out?
帮你忙吗
You need help?
当然
Of course. That's
这就是我的职责
That's what I do.
很好
Great.
可以帮我移走钢琴吗
Could you move the piano for me?
这琴才重五百磅  很轻的  不是吗
it's 500 pounds. That's not too much, Is it?
你有东西落卡在钢琴下面还是怎样
Well, is there something trapped underneath or...?
没有  我只是想把它从窗户边移开
No. I just want to move it away from the window.
很抱歉  我的力气不足以移动钢琴
I'm sorry my powers aren't for frivolous just one quick lift.
你究竟想干什么
Why are you doing that?
豪斯  这与你无关
House, it's none of your business.
我很好奇
I'm curious.
作为一个医生  你到底在干什么
As a doctor, what are you doing?
如果他是自由战士的话  他就不必呆在这里
Either he is Freedom Master, and he shouldn't be here,
除非他有严重危险的妄想症
Or else he's suffering from a serious and dangerous delusion
他必须接受事实
That he needs to deal with.
那么
So...
这是合理的医学动机
Legit medical reasons.
你不会是仅仅因为他些许与众不同
You're not just trying to break the guy
就想让他崩溃吧
Because he's a little different.
他与常人无异  他只是有妄想症
He's not different. He's delusional.
-你到底能不能帮我  -她在看什么
- Can you help me out? - What is she looking at?
史蒂夫  你不是超级英雄
You're not a superhero, Steven.
-你只是凡夫俗子  -我能救她
- You're just a regular person. - I can save her.
没什么大不了的  我们都是凡夫俗子
That's okay. We'rewe're all just regular people.
我们都是这样
It's what we do.
他们偷了她的音乐盒
They stole her voice box.
他们放在那里
They have it in there.
所以她才一直盯着那里
That's what she's staring at.
这就是她一直盯着的东西
-她一直盯着  -你妻子已经走了
- She's always staring. - Your wife is dead.
正义必将战胜邪恶
Good can defeat evil.
并非永远如此
Not every time.
那天邪恶的人杀死了很多好人
Evil people killed a lot of good people that day.
你无力拯救你妻子  没人可以
You couldn't save her. No one could save her.
就在那里
It's in there.
她的音乐在那里
Her voice is in there.
灰色警报
Code gray.
她的音乐在
Her voice is in
她的音乐在那里
Her voice is in there!
他的音乐在那里
在那里啊
Is there
别
No!
千万别
Don't do it.
我什么都没干
I'm not doing anything.
你在思考
You're thinking.
在这个地方思考会一发不可收拾
Things go from thinking to doing way too fast in this place.
你继续想下去  你就会一无所有
You keep thinking, you're gonna wind up with no mo in your mojo.
我想再揍你一顿
I'm thinking of hitting you again.
你讨厌麦地那  你讨厌他们所有人
You hate Medina. You hate all of them.
你想让他们日子不好过
You want to hurt them.
但你得放下仇恨  继续假装合作
You got to keep pretending. Step away from the hate.
假装的合作与真正的合作有什么不同
What's the difference between pretending to cooperate and cooperating?
假装就是假装  不是真的
Pretending is pretending. It's not real.
你不是真的要合作
You don't mean it.
我呆坐在那里看着他
I sat and watched
做些愚蠢至极且毫无意义的事
While he did something stupid and pointless.
我是配合了
I cooperated.
过不了几天  你就不再需要这么做了
In a few days, you won't have to watch,
你就能回家了
Because you're going home.
你可以要回你的工作
You'll be getting your job back.
大家都进来
Everybody inside!
欢送会要开始了
Closing ceremonies.
人人都参加  有人要回家了
Everyone attends. One of you is going home.
这个星期很棒
It's been a great week.
许多人都突飞猛进
Um, a number of you have made tremendous strides.
今天我们欢聚一堂祝贺
But today we're here to congratulate
苏珊
Susan.
我们为你骄傲
We're proud of her!
我们祝她一路走好
We wish her well, and we hope
而且一去不复返
To never see her again!
真漂亮  不是吗
Yeah, isn't it pretty?
比斯利医生  你愿意来切蛋糕吗
And, um, Dr. Beasley, do you want to cut the cake?
当然  很乐意
Yeah, I'll do that.
好的
Okay.
自由战士在哪
Where's Freedom Master?
他不能来参加
He isn't able to take part.
滚出来
Get out there.
他们说人人都要参加
They said everybody has to get out there.
说话啊  开口啊
Talk! Say something!
豪斯医生  别烦他了
Dr. House, leave him alone.
你给他下药了吗
Did you drug him?
当然没有
Of course I didn't drug him.
他面无表情  这是典型的紧张症
He's in flat affect. He's practically catatonic.
这里有蛋糕哦
Hey, we got cake.
-他没事的  -双层巧克力哦
- He's fine. - Double chocolate.
-好好吃哦  -别跟我说他没事
- Yummy, yummy. - Don't tell me that he's fine!
是你干的好事
You did this!
他以前很正常
He was functioning.
-很开心  -他有妄想症
- He was happy. - He was delusional.
那又怎么样
Yeah.
他现在这样真的"好"多了
He's way better off now.
豪斯医生
Dr. House...
我们谈谈
Let's talk.
思考坏事
Thinking sucks.
我还没有权力生气吗
I'm not allowed to get angry?
他们在整他
They screwed him up.
还有在积分上
And for the record...
我比苏珊高两级
I am two privilege levels above Susan,
我和她的抑郁量分数也一样
And I got the same depression-scale score.
每个病人都是不同的
Every patient is different.
与分数无关
It's not about scores
-与等级也无关  -快乐就是快乐
- And levels and... - Happiness is happiness.
测试是测试  应对是应对
The test is the test. Coping is coping.
-你以为你能应付自如  -当然
- And you think you're... - Absolutely!
我要解决更深层的问题
I need to address some deeper issues,
我能为门诊病人带来福音
Which I can do on an outpatient basis.
一周三小时可否
Three hours a week?
这仅仅是我的初步提议
And that's just my opening offer.
如果你想要商量的话  我很乐意
If you want to counter, I'll likely fold.
不行
No.
否定可不是辩论
"No" is not an argument.
你想挫败我吗
Are you trying to frustrate me?
不是
No.
又是否定吗
"No" again?
我能应对  我应对自如
I can cope! I'm coping.
事实上
In fact...
我应对能力比你所想要好得多
I'm coping better than you think.
我没有吃过你们开的药
I've not been taking my meds,
一颗也没有
Not one.
即便如此  我仍在你的忧虑度测试中得高分
And yet, I still scored a "high functioning" on your depression test.
你用来证明你已经好了的证据就是谎言吗
So your proof of your well-being is that you lied?
是操纵
Manipulated.
我要证明的是
My proof is
我能骗过测试  我能骗过你
That I can fool the test, I can fool you,
这就证明了我是一个很正常的人
Which means I am high functioning.
我神志清醒  意志健全  才华横溢
I am sane, rational, capable.
我不应该被关在这里
I should not be here.
这是你今天要吃的药吗
These are your pills from today?
我不会吃的
I'm not gonna take it.
我只会再次扔掉
I'll just cheek it again.
舔舔吧
Lick it.
你要我舔你的脏手吗
You want me to lick your hand?
我洗过手了
I washed.
是糖
It's sugar.
你的测试结果
Your test results
进步得太有规律
Were improving too regularly
并且太过迅速
And too quickly.
我担心你没有用药
I was concerned that you weren't taking your pills,
担心这都是装出来的
That it was all an act,
所以我把你的药换成安慰剂
So I switched you to a placebo...
看你
To see if your...
能不能持续进步
Improvements would continue.
你的精神测试对我来说毫无反馈
Your psych tests told me nothing,
是你的尿液测试
But your urine tests
漏出了马脚
Told me you were faking.
你得停止与这里抗争
You need to stop fighting the system.
你得让我尽职尽责
You need to let me do my job.
所以
So...
你下一计划是什么呢
What's the next plan?
没有新计划
There is no new plan.
我黔驴技穷了
I'm out of plans.
那我们该做什么
So what do we do?
别再说话
We stop talking.
我看见你车子后座有大提琴
I see you've got some cello in your trunk.
不该这么说  不够婉转
And, no, that's not a euphemism.
你在监视我吗
Are you spying on me?
我住在精神病院
I'm living in a psychiatric hospital.
我们唯一能做的就是眺望
Staring out of the window is what we do.
我还以为你要人帮忙能把它搬上来
I assume you'll need help carrying it up.
我还是有去楼下的特权
I still got grounds privileges.
如果你去搬大提琴的话  谁来搬你
And who's going to carry you when you're carrying the cello?
那是  把一个无用的跛子撇在一边
Yes, cast aside the useless cripple
真像德国佬
How very German of you.
说真的  那东西加上箱子有一吨重
Seriously, the thing weighs a ton with that case.
我想我需要个手推车
I think I'll need a dolly.
或者可以让超人先生把它弄进去
Or we could ask Clark Kent to pitch in.
手推车比较好办
The dolly's probably easier.
手推车那家伙
Eh, the dolly...
已经自我感觉良好了
Already feels good about itself.
他本是个无忧无虑的超级英雄
He was a happy-go-lucky superhero
直到有人跟他说  他没有超能力
Until they told him he has no powers.
我们让他帮忙  他会好很多
We let him help out, he feels good about himself.
可能不会那么沮丧
Might be less depressed.
为什么你把自己的生命耽误在
Why do you put your life on hold
每星期花五天来看你家小姑子呢
To visit your sister-in-law five times a week?
我像是一个冷漠无情的坏人吗
Am I somehow a bad person for showing compassion?
不像
No.
你是一个连说谎都不会的坏人
You're not even a bad person for lying about why you're doing it.
好厉害哦
Oh, that is impressive.
好一双超级金刚腿
That is a superhuman feat.
你为什么不在飞回病房前先歇歇呢
Why don't you take a rest before you fly that thing up to the ward?
他还是很沮丧
He's still depressed.
把你车钥匙给我
Give me your car keys.
你要拿钥匙在他面前晃一晃来逗他吗
You gonna dangle them in front of him to entertain him?
我想给他飞翔的感觉
I'm gonna make him feel like he's flying.
我只是想载他兜兜风  从斜坡上冲下来
I'll just drive him around the grounds, top down,
让风吹拂他的秀发
Wind in his hair.
说真的
Seriously...
连这个你都能抗拒吗
You're gonna say no to that?
你为什么对我那么好
Why are you so nice to me?
我觉得你心地善良
I think you have a good heart.
如果我说我是撒谎的你仍会对我好吗
Would you still be nice to me if I told you that I lied?
我并不仅仅是要你的敞篷车兜兜风
I'm not just driving around the grounds in your convertible
而是在绑架他  还要抢你的车
I'm kidnapping him and stealing your car.
你确定吗
You sure?
我才觉得我们擦出火花
I was just starting to feel a little heat between us.
觉得咱们有点像《雌雄大盗》的男女主角
Thought we had kind of a "Bonnie and Clyde" thing going there.
他俩最后被乱枪打死
Bonnie and clyde get shot to pieces.
再见
Hmm. see you.
你能行的
You can do this.
紧握我的手  我也能做到
If you hold my hand, I can do it too.
别放手
Don't let go!
再飞高点
Going up!
自由战士回来啦
Freedom Master's back!
降落吧  自由战士
Keep it down, Freedom Master.
你把平民百姓吓着了
You're scaring the good citizens.
这是我一生中最美妙的时刻
That was the coolest moment of my life.
是很好玩
It was fun.
你可以骂诺兰是白痴来报答我
You can repay me by telling Nolan he's an idiot.
呼吸清新的空气
Smell that fresh air
还有享受金色阳光的温暖
And the warmth of your yellow sun.
我们确实很尽兴
We do enjoy it.
得小心开车
Careful of the traffic.
我不想撞坏栏杆
Don't go damaging any fenders.
别这样  快下来
Come on, get down.
没有人喊救命
There's no cry for help.
没有小猫卡在树上
There's no cat in a tree.
谢谢你  格雷戈
Thank you, Greg.
不要
No!
他大难不死
he's lucky to be alive.
他胰脏破裂
He's got a lacerated spleen,
骨盆旋转型骨折
Rotational pelvic fracture,
股骨肱骨多重骨折
Compound break of the femur and humerus.
你一生都在寻求真相
Everything in your life has been about finding the truth.
可突然  你对他
But suddenly, with this guy,
你要加剧这个病人的妄想
You decide to reinforce a sick man's delusions.
你只想用他来打击我  对吧
You just wanted to take a swing at me, hmm?
你不在乎要出院
You don't care about getting out.
你不在乎他
You don't care about him.
你甚至不在乎真相
You don't even care about the truth.
你什么都不在乎  豪斯
You don't care about anything, House.
我会把你转去温斯洛精神病院
I'm transferring you to Winslow psychiatric.
祝你在他们那里能得逞
You'll have better luck pulling the wool over their eyes.
我受够了
I'm done.
不要
Don't.